suppose that the instruction we fetch
here is a jump instruction next cycle
this jump moves here the problem is we
fetch this jump but in this cycle here
we didn't even know what it is so when
it moves here the next instruction we
fetch will be the one that follows this
jump in memory so we will have for
example a subtract that never should
have been fetched cuz we should have
fetched from the location where the jump
is going but at this point where we
needed to decide what to fetch we didn't
even know that it's a jump meanwhile we
are decoding the jump so at the end of
this cycle we will know it's a jump but
we may not know where it's going so now
let's say that here we figure out this
is a jump and where it's going meanwhile
our subtract has moved here something
else has been fetched from the location
where we shouldn't have been fetching
things at all and now we figure out that
really we should be fetching from
somewhere else so what happens now is
called a pipeline flush what we do is we
convert these fetched instructions into
pipeline Bubbles and then as the jump
moves on these two bubbles will also
move on and now we will fetch the
correct instruction that should have
been fetched right after the jump so as
you can see a jump in this case because
it caused the pipeline flush has two
bubbles that follow it and only then we
have the next instruction so if we count
for these two instructions what the CPI
is it's actually Four cycles for only
the two instructions so as you can see
these pipeline flushes are going to be
an additional source of having a CPI
larger than one